[
    {
        "question" : "A line which cuts a pair of parallel lines is called",
        "optionA" : "tangent",
        "optionB" : "chord",
        "optionC" : "traversal",
        "optionD" : "intersector",
        "answer" : "traversal"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An angle whose value is ____, is called complete angle.",
        "optionA" : "180°",
        "optionB" : " 240°",
        "optionC" : " 360°",
        "optionD" : "None of the above",
        "answer" : "360°"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The areas of two similar triangles are 81 sq. cm and 49 sq. cm. Find the ratio of their corresponding heights.",
        "optionA" : "9:7",
        "optionB" : "7:9",
        "optionC" : "6:5",
        "optionD" : "81:49",
        "answer" : "9:7"
    },
    
    {
        "question" : "Consider ΔABD such that angle ADB = 20° and C is a point on BD such that AB=AC and CD=CA. Then the measure of angle ABC is",
        "optionA" : "30°",
        "optionB" : "40°",
        "optionC" : "45°",
        "optionD" : "60°",
        "answer" : "40°"
    },


    {
        "question" : "If the length and breadth of a rectangle are increased by a% and b% respectively, then the area will be increased by",
        "optionA" : "(a-b+2ab/100)%",
        "optionB" : " (a+b+2ab/100)%",
        "optionC" : " a+b+ab/100)%(",
        "optionD" : " (a+b+ab/100)%",
        "answer" : "a+b+ab/100)%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A, B and C can complete a piece of work in 14, 6 and 12 days respectively. Working together, they will complete the work in",
        "optionA" : "19/9 days",
        "optionB" : "27 days",
        "optionC" : "28/9 days",
        "optionD" : "25/8 days",
        "answer" : "28/9 days"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If Px = Qy = Rz  and Q/P = R/Q, then 2z/(x+z) = ?",
        "optionA" : " y/z",
        "optionB" : " y/x",
        "optionC" : " x/y",
        "optionD" : " z/y",
        "answer" : "y/x"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper purchases 15 mangoes for Rs. 10 and sells them at 10 mangoes for Rs. 15. Thus, he earns a profit of",
        "optionA" : " 50%",
        "optionB" : "75%",
        "optionC" : "80%",
        "optionD" : "125%",
        "answer" : "125%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "4950/6 + 112 x 1.75 = ? x 2",
        "optionA" : " 510.5",
        "optionB" : "505.2",
        "optionC" : " 515.5",
        "optionD" : "none of the above",
        "answer" : "510.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If a certain sum of money can become 5 times of its principal in 10 years, then the rate of interest is",
        "optionA" : "20%",
        "optionB" : "30%",
        "optionC" : "40%",
        "optionD" : "50%",
        "answer" : "40%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An amount of Rs. 10,000 becomes Rs. 20,736 in 2 years. If the rate of interest is compounded half yearly, what is the annual rate of interest?",
        "optionA" : "25%",
        "optionB" : "20%",
        "optionC" : "40%",
        "optionD" : "30%",
        "answer" : "40%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What will come in the place of question mark (?) in the following series? 2, 5, 7, 12, 19, 31, 50, ?",
        "optionA" : "81",
        "optionB" : "74",
        "optionC" : "69",
        "optionD" : " none of the above",
        "answer" : "81"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In an equilateral triangle has the height of 12 cm then what is the area of the triangle?",
        "optionA" : "42√3 c.c",
        "optionB" : "48√3 c.c",
        "optionC" : " 24√3 c.c",
        "optionD" : "34√3 c.c",
        "answer" : " 24√3 c.c"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The monthly income and monthly expenditure ratio of A and B are 5:6 and 4:5 respectively. If both of them can have Rs. 500 as monthly savings, then what is the income of A?",
        "optionA" : "Rs. 3,000",
        "optionB" : "Rs, 500",
        "optionC" : "Rs. 5,000",
        "optionD" : "Rs. 2,500",
        "answer" : "Rs. 2,500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find out the least number which when multiplied by 45, the result becomes a perfect square.",
        "optionA" : "9",
        "optionB" : "15",
        "optionC" : "5",
        "optionD" : " None of the above",
        "answer" : "5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "(175)2 – (75)2 = ?",
        "optionA" : "5000",
        "optionB" : "20000",
        "optionC" : "25000",
        "optionD" : " None of the above",
        "answer" : "None of the above"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If a = (√3+1)/(√3-1) and b = (√3-1)/(√3+1) then (a2+ab+b2)/(a2-ab+b2) = ?",
        "optionA" : "15/11",
        "optionB" : " 17/11",
        "optionC" : "19/11",
        "optionD" : "1",
        "answer" : "1"
    },
    {
        "question" : " If the fractions 3/5, 2/3, ¼, 5/7 and 6/11 are arranged in ascending order of their values, then which one will be the fourth",
        "optionA" : "3/5",
        "optionB" : "1/4",
        "optionC" : "5/7",
        "optionD" : "2/3",
        "answer" : "2/3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "1 hectare = ?",
        "optionA" : "1000 m2",
        "optionB" : "10000 m2",
        "optionC" : "100000 m2",
        "optionD" : "None of the above",
        "answer" : "10000 m2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The sum of two numbers is 24 and the sum of their squares is 386, then one number is",
        "optionA" : "17",
        "optionB" : "19",
        "optionC" : "9",
        "optionD" : "11",
        "answer" : "19"
    }
]

